<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Pawn Chronicles: Personal Epics</name>
  <author>D4egon</author>
  <packageId>D4egon.PawnChronicles</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>

  <description>
Every pawn carries an unfinished story. Pawn Chronicles reads who they actually are - their traits, skills, history, relationships, and the state of the world around them - and builds a living narrative around them in real time.

No two arcs are the same. Everything is composed at runtime from the pawn's actual data.

HOW IT WORKS
(I went with a fire theme for flavor, ecause I like fire and D, C, B, A, SS seems boring ^^)

Sparks and Embers fire quietly throughout the day - small moments of texture the game noticed. A first kill. A pain spike. A bond forming. These stamp a chronicle entry and may leave a mood memory, but ask nothing of you.

When the weight accumulates, an Arc begins.

Arcs are personal quest chains. They appear in the quest tab with a timer, demand real decisions, and resolve with permanent consequences. The pawn is changed - their adulthood backstory can be rewritten on success or failure, world events can follow, factions can shift.

ARC TIERS

Kindle - 3 stages. The first real demand. Mood consequences only.
Flame - 4 stages. Minor faction touches.
Fire - 5 stages. The pawn is permanently changed. Backstory rewritten, so be careful.
Inferno - 5 stages with a mid-arc branch driven by the pawn's dominant tag.
Hellfire - A chain of linked epics, escalating.

ENTANGLED ARCS

Some stories belong to two people. Rivalry. Mentorship. Grief shared between survivors. Entangled arcs bind two colonists into a single shared quest - one story, two protagonists, one outcome.

PLAYER CHOICES

At key moments, the arc offers branching choices shaped by the pawn's dominant tags. Who they are determines what options appear. What you choose shapes what they become.

FULL TRANSPARENCY

Every mechanical consequence announces itself plainly. Nothing fires invisibly.
"The arc sparked an inspiration - Inspired Shooting."
"The weight broke them. They've entered a sad wandering state."
"Something fell near the pawn."

REQUIREMENTS

Harmony (required). Nothing else.

COMPATIBILITY

Compatible with most mods. The scraper reads any content registered in RimWorld's DefDatabases - custom traits, genes, factions, world objects, and backstories from other mods are incorporated into arc grammar automatically.

Made for people who want even more depth to their colonists.


SETTINGS:

You can adjust everything to your liking in the mod settings.
  </description>

  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>

  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
